## **Muhammad Hassan Shehzad**

Software Engineer

Address: Silicon Gates 1, Silicon Oasis - Dubai Email: engr.hassan2k9@gmail.com,
Mobile: +971585619897,



### Statement:

"Software Engineer with over 3 years' experience of development in a multitude of different web-based languages and tech to develop websites, programs and platform independent 2d games using html5 canvas tag and JavaScript libraries like <a href="mailto:createJS suite">createJS suite</a> and <a href="mailto:TweenMax">TweenMax</a>."

## Work Experience:

- Project manager & Developer at Radiance studio was my own startup along with another partner. I was the project manager and lead developer. I used to coordinate with the clients on a day to day basis and kept them updated on the project milestones. Major clients were from America, Malaysia and Pakistan.
  - **Software engineer at "rgnix-IT"** (July 2013-October2015).
  - Website and game Developer at Upwork & Fiverr. (July 2013-current)

# **Education:**

- BS Software Engineering UET Taxila Pakistan (2009 –2013)
- Intermediate in Computer Science
   Punjab College, Satellite Town, Rawalpindi
   (2008 2009)
- Matriculation
   Fauji Foundation College, Rawalpindi (2005 2006)

### Personal information:

Date of Birth: March 1990
 Nationality: Pakistani
 Marital status: Single

Languages English and Urdu

Languages JavaScript, AJAX, C++, Java, html5, CSS3.0, PHP, Python  Framework's createJS Suite jQuery+ Howler.JS Tween Max  Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime Text, Photoshop, Trello  S/5 (FAIR)  4.5/5 (VERY STRONG) 3/5 (FAIR)  4.5/5 (VERY STRONG)  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)	Technical Skills	
html5, CSS3.0, PHP, Python  Framework's createJS Suite jQuery+ Howler.JS Tween Max  Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	<u>Languages</u>	Expertise Level
Framework's createJS Suite jQuery+ Howler.JS Tween Max  Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	JavaScript, AJAX, C++, Java,	3/5 ( FAIR)
createJS Suite jQuery+ Howler.JS Tween Max  Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL  Platforms: Windows Linux  Linux  4.55 (VERY STRONG) 3/5 (FAIR)  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  Content Management System WordPress  4/5  4/5  4/5  Content Management System W/5  4/5  4/5  Content Management System W/5  A/5  Content Management System W/5  Content Management System W/5  A/5  A/5  Content Management System W/5  A/5  Content Management System W/7  A/5  A/5  A/5  A/5  A/5  A/5  A/5  A	html5, CSS3.0, PHP, Python	
createJS Suite jQuery+ Howler.JS Tween Max  Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL  Platforms: Windows Linux  Linux  4.55 (VERY STRONG) 3/5 (FAIR)  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  4/5  Content Management System WordPress  4/5  4/5  4/5  Content Management System W/5  4/5  4/5  Content Management System W/5  A/5  Content Management System W/5  Content Management System W/5  A/5  A/5  Content Management System W/5  A/5  Content Management System W/7  A/5  A/5  A/5  A/5  A/5  A/5  A/5  A		
jQuery+ Howler.JS Tween Max  Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		A F /F /VEDV CTDONO
Howler.JS Tween Max  Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		
Tween Max  Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		· · ·
Content Management System WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		
WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	Tween Max	3/5
WordPress  Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		
Search Engine Optimization (SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL 4/5 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		4/5
(SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL 4/5 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	Wordi icss	7/3
(SEO)  Databases: MySQL SQL 4/5 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	Search Engine Optimization	
MySQL 4/5 SQL 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	· ·	
MySQL 4/5 SQL 4/5  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		
SQL  Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	<u>Databases:</u>	
Platforms: Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	MySQL	4/5
Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	SQL	4/5
Windows Linux  Tools: Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		
Linux <u>Tools:</u> Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		
<u>Tools:</u> Github, Visual Studio, Sublime		
Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	Linux	
Github, Visual Studio, Sublime	Tools:	

## Accomplishments:

- 2nd position holder in "Intermediate of Computer Science" Rawalpindi board, Pakistan.
- Honored as a state guest of Pakistan and awarded \$3K by Chief Minister of Punjab Pakistan.

# Projects worth mentioning:

### 1. Desert Rush:

Desert Rush is a simple puzzle game that lets players create massive combos to kill the enemy and upgrade to the next level.

**Play Now** 

## 2. Animal Quest

Puzzle game with additional twist. Touch similar blocks to pop out and explore three lands and along the way be ready to find the amazing cute animals. Highly Addictive, packed with cuteness.

Play Now

### 3. Educational Games for kids:

Media Corp used my services to build their children gaming portal.

- ♣ -Couple of games worth mentioning in this regard
  - **Hoppy Counts it Play Now**
  - **❖** Bin It <u>Play Now</u>

#### 4. Tarot Card Game:

Card game about connection with universe, animated and made completely with CREATEJS and Tween Max suite inside canvas tag of html5.

**Play Now** 

## 5. Gift of Alchemy:

Addictive Puzzle game.

**Play Now** 

### 6. Number Cards Game:

Card game for children to teach them numbers and their different functions.

**Play Now** 

### 7. Educational Game Portal for kids:

I recently developed and integrated all the 8 games mentioned in this gaming portal for an American Client. I was the sole developer of all the 8 games.

<u>Dictadoescolar</u>

# 8. CamAli 3d game:

Game under-development for an American Client for his popular cartoon series camali. Camali

## Websites:

Some of the latest websites developed are as follows:

- One Source Solicitors UK
- <u>Urban Media Tod</u>ay
- South Florida Real Estate Buzz
- UK sofas
- <u>Dictadoescolar</u>
- Camali
- Just Immigration Law UK (under development)

References: available upon request.